Inventory of the Martin Parks Burks Papers 1798-1866
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Martin Parks Burks Papers 1798-1866
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Mss. 39.1 B91
4,301 items.
Accounts, receipts, and business letters of Martin P. Burks, sheriff of Bedford County, Virginia.
Martin Parks Burks
Administrative Information
Restrictions on Access
Collection is open to all researchers.
Acquisition Information
Purchased: 4,301 items, 1939.
Biographical/Historical Information
Martin Parks Burks was the deputy sheriff of Bedford County, Virginia.
Scope and Content Information
Chiefly accounts, receipts and business letters of Martin P. Burks, 1798-1866, including records while he was deputy sheriff of Bedford County, Virginia.
Arrangement
Arrangement
Collection is arranged chronologically.
Organization
The collection has been broken down into three series. Series 1 are the accounts of Thomas Turpin, Series 2 are the papers relating to the sheriff's office of Bedford County, and Series 3 are the personal papers of Martin P. Burks.
Index Terms
Subjects
Sheriffs--Virginia--History--19th century.; Bedford County (Va.)--History--19th century.; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865.; Bedford County (Va.)-- Sheriffs.
Persons:
Turpin, Thomas.; Bedford County, (Va.). Sheriff.
Contents List
- Chiefly accounts of Thomas Turpin. 1798-1809 (Folder 1)
- Bedford County Sheriff's Papers. 1810-1829. (Folder 2-7)
  - Chiefly Bedford County, Virginia Sheriff's Papers. 1810-1819. (Folder 2-3)
  - Chiefly Bedford County, Virginia Sheriff's Papers. 1820-1839 (Folder 4-7)
- Mostly personal papers of Martin Parks Burks. 1830-1866 (Folder 8-19)
  - Personal accounts, and receipts, business letters, and a few papers of the Bedford County, Virginia Sheriff's Office. 1830-1839 (Folder 8-9)
  - Accounts, receipts and business letters. 1840-1849. (Folder 10-11)
  - Accounts, receipts and business letters. 1850-1859. (Folder 12-15.)
  - Business letters, letters concerning the Civil War and accounts. 1860-1866. (Folder 16)
  - Accounts, receipts and business letters. undated. (Folder 17-18.)
  - Fragments. undated. (Folder 19)